hey everyone welcome again to another
interesting lesson in this task
automation course today we are going to
talk about a new identification
mechanism provided by Tosca
now until now all our controls which we
have used in earlier sessions have been
identified by the properties
present in the web application
but what if two controls are present in
a web page which have got similar
properties and you cannot find a unique
property to identify a particular
control
now this is a very common scenario which
you will face while automating any web
application
so Tosca provides you a way of
identifying your controls in different
ways so identifying by properties is
just one mechanism there are many other
mechanisms which is present in Tosca in
order to help you to identify controls
uniquely on the web pages
so let's look at an example
on how a control can look similar to
another control having the same
properties and why you cannot identify
it uniquely using the properties
so for this I have gone to google.com
and if you look here there is a button
called Google Search right so if we type
anything here
and now we want to click on this Google
search button right so this is our
scenario a very simple scenario but what
will happen is uh when you try to
automate this you will find that Google
search is not unique now how I can tell
I will show it in Tosca but before that
I can also show it using the inspect
element right so when I do a inspect on
this
and I can show you using the properties
that this particular value
or this button is not unique right so
let's see uh so this is the input class
right and it has got a value Google
search you can see there is a name which
looks like a unique right and let's try
and use it okay so I'm going to manually
type this uh XPath so that we can see
that this is not a unique control right
so I'm going to say at name equals
BTN K right
um and ideally this should be identified
using this XPath
but if you look carefully there are one
of two controls using the same export
right
so if although it's not visible
on this page there are two controls
having the same properties
which are exactly similar so it's very
difficult to uniquely identify this
Google search button right now one way
is you can use the index right index of
this button to identify this the other
way around is to use a anchor now anchor
is basically a control which is present
uh within the range of this particular
control which you are trying to identify
right so it's basically a relationship
with this button right anything which is
unique uh within the range of this
particular button right so I can either
use this text box as an anchor or I can
use this another button I am feeling
lucky as the anchor for this particular
button right when we come to Tosca okay
so let me go ahead and scan this module
and show it to you how it looks like
so I am going to create another folder
here
so let's go ahead and scan our
application so right click on the folder
and select scan select application
now select the application which you
want to scan for us it is the Google
Chrome uh with the Google web page so
select that and click on scan
now this opens uh the basic View Window
where I can select my controls and add
to my module right so I'm going to
select this text box and this Google
search button right
now once I do that you will see a orange
highlighted bar on the Google search
button right and that will tell me that
this particular button is not unique
right so this item was not uniquely
selected by Tosca using the properties
which are present on the web page
now to look a bit deeper we need to go
to the advanced window right to the
advanced view where we get all the
different controls which are present on
this web page with their properties okay
now as this item is not unique our first
attempt should be to add more properties
right to make it unique
so let's try to add some more properties
to see whether we can make this control
unique using additional properties right
so let's select type and value but as
you see even adding these two properties
is not making this control unique right
in situations like this as I explained
there are other ways of identifying a
particular control right so if I go to
the advanced view on the top menu you
will see identify by option and this is
the properties uh option which we are
using right identifying controls by
properties but Tosca provides you with
different other mechanisms okay so one
is identified by anchor it also provides
you identified by image and identify by
index now we are going to talk about how
we can identify controls by image and
index
but your second option after properties
should always be anchor
right so let's go ahead and select this
and you will see on the right side there
is a window called identifier by anchor
now Tosca will sometimes automatically
select anchor control for you right so
it has got this relative algorithm and
there are different options here right
so we are not going to go deep into this
algorithm which Tosca uses but for just
for your knowledge you can select auto
always and it will automatically select
anchor control for you or you can also
choose shortest path and coordinate
right
so it will try to find a anchor control
based on three different algorithms but
I have selected Auto right uh so it is
not able to identify automatically
anchor control
um at the same time I can add my own
anchor control right so the easiest way
is to just uh drag a particular control
into this text box okay so I have
dragged this I'm feeling lucky button
into this anchor control and here you
will get the message that the target
control was successfully identified
right and we can also add another anchor
control right so you can just click on
select on screen and select that
particular control to add as your anchor
control so we can have multiple hacker
controls if it is not able to identify
with a single control okay
now if you see on this Google search
button uh the message has changed to
select item is unique and that orange
bar is also disappeared
which means all our controls are now
unique in this module and we can go
ahead and create our test case right so
let me go ahead and save this and close
this window so that will create my
module here
and I'm going to rename this to
something uh useful which is Google
Search right
and we are going to create a test case
now okay so I've created a new folder
here I'm going to add a test case called
Google search
and then I'm going to add my test step
which is basically the module so I'm
going to search my Google search module
I am going to double click on this so
that it can add that right and
here I'm going to enter some text say
Tosca right and here I'm going to click
on this so
um I can select the click option here
right so it's going to enter Tosca into
the text box and it is going to click on
it okay so that's that's our scenario
so let's go ahead and run this for now
and see if it's working or not
so it's going to type Tosca into the
text box it's going to click on the
Google search button and it is going to
display the results right
so this is how you can identify controls
using anchor control if there are
scenarios where you are not able to
identify uniquely any control using all
the properties present on the screen
right so this is another way of
identifying your controls
so that's all about how to identify
controls in Tosca using the anchor
property or anchor control
uh hopefully this was useful I'm going
to talk about uh all the different
mechanisms which are still present in
Tosca to identify controls like identify
by image and identify by index
so keep watching and do subscribe to our
channel uh we'll uh bring up another new
Tosca lesson next Friday until then keep
learning and have a nice day